avma.org 2016-03-23

# Privacy Policy for AVMA Websites

​ 

_Updated May 23, 2013_

This is the American Veterinary Medical Association® (“AVMA”) privacy policy applicable to any site containing the URL avma.org and any other websites operated by the AVMA (collectively referred to as the “AVMA Websites”) from time to time. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully as well as the Agreement and Terms of Use applicable to use of the AVMA Websites.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, you can send us an email at [avmaonline@avma.org](mailto:avmaonline@avma.org), call us at 800.248.2862, or write to us at:

            American Veterinary Medical Association  
            1931 N. Meacham Road, Suite 100  
            Schaumburg, IL 60173-4360

### Overview

AVMA values individual privacy, and we want to give visitors to AVMA Websites the opportunity to know what information we collect about them, what we do with that information, and how they can limit the use of personally-identifiable information beyond the purposes for which they first provided it. _At all times, however, AVMA reserves the right to disclose information where required by law or to comply with valid legal process (such as a search warrant, subpoena, or court order), to protect AVMA’s rights or property, including without limitation in the event of a transfer of control of AVMA or substantially all of its assets, or during emergencies when safety is at risk._

AVMA reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at its discretion with or without providing notice to users of AVMA Websites. Whenever we change this Privacy Policy, however, we will endeavor to give users of AVMA Websites reasonable notice by posting a notice on the home page of www.avma.org. Since these policy change notices last only for a limited time, you should check this Privacy Policy regularly to see if there have been any changes. 

### Data We Collect and How We Use It

We do not collect personally identifiable information, such as your name, address, phone number or email address, if you are only browsing AVMA Websites and do not interact for any online product or service from the AVMA. We do, however, collect certain non-personally identifiable information from all visitors to AVMA Websites, as described more fully below.

We will collect and retain certain personal information from you when needed to process your transactions (including purchases of goods and services), fulfill your requests for information, allow you to access certain services or areas of AVMA Websites such as online communities, or maintain our membership records. The type of personal information we collect will vary but may include your name, contact information (address, phone number, billing and delivery information, email address), credit card or other financial account information, and other demographic information. The type of information you provide will determine the personal information that is collected.

If you purchase a product or service at any AVMA Website, we will not give out your credit card number or other financial account information to third parties unless you authorize us to do so, or it is necessary to fulfill our responsibilities with respect to the transaction, including but not limited to delivering a product or service you order.

Our online member directory contains specific personal and professional information, depending on the information you provide to the AVMA through your membership application or updates to your online profile. Access to online member directory information is available only to AVMA members. However, we may occasionally provide, sell, or rent limited member data to third parties, such as companies that offer products and services related to veterinary medicine for sale to AVMA members. See below for more information on AVMA’s information-sharing practices.

We do collect and store information that does not identify you personally when you visit AVMA Websites, including but not limited to: the name of the domain and host from which you access the AVMA Websites; the Internet protocol address used to access AVMA Websites; the date and time you access AVMA Websites; and the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to AVMA Websites. We use this information to track and analyze traffic to AVMA Websites, including the number of visitors and which pages are viewed by visitors, and to help us improve AVMA Websites. We may also share this information in aggregate with advertisers and sponsors to determine advertising effectiveness.

Like most websites, we employ cookies to assist users to more efficiently use AVMA Websites. A “cookie” is a string of information that is sent by a website and stored on a user’s computer. Cookie information is used only by the AVMA and our contractors, and is not provided to other organizations. You may block cookies by modifying the cookie option in your browser’s settings, but doing so may inhibit certain features or services of AVMA Websites from being accessible or functioning properly.

### Email Policy

We do not share, sell or rent email addresses to anyone outside the AVMA except in the following circumstances:  

  * If needed for vendors to provide services to the AVMA (for example, when using a third-party vendor to send an email); or
  * If the Executive Vice President, using his/her discretion, deems it appropriate to share this information with certain related organizations, such as the AVMA Group Health and Life Insurance Trust, the AVMA Professional Liability Insurance Trust, or constituent and allied organizations. 

We sometimes collect specific information on email responses, such as how many recipients open an email or choose to click through to links provided in the email message. This information is used solely within the AVMA to analyze areas of interest and to enhance our products, services, and AVMA Websites. None of this information is sold or distributed outside the AVMA. You can manage your email preferences, including opt-out preferences, in our [Email Subscription Center](http://avma.highroadsolution.com/avma_preference_center/default.aspx). 

### Sharing Personal Information Other than Email Address

AVMA may share, sell, or rent limited member data, including postal address, to third parties, including companies that offer products and services related to veterinary medicine for sale to AVMA members. This includes, for example, companies that offer products and services to members through the AVMA affinity programs. In addition, AVMA may share limited personal information of registered AVMA Convention attendees with convention exhibitors. AVMA also hires vendors to perform certain services for the AVMA, such as packaging and mailing purchases, printing, and sending postal mail and processing event registration. We only provide the information these companies need to perform these services.

As an AVMA member, if you prefer to receive mailings from AVMA only and do not wish to receive mailings from these other organizations, you may have your name and address removed from the lists. To do so, please visit My Profile and update your member preferences to be excluded from third party mailing opportunities. 

### Security

AVMA uses up-to-date technology to keep any information you provide as secure as possible. We also have in place privacy protection control contractual obligations with our vendors designed to ensure that personal information is protected from unauthorized access or disclosure. AVMA employees are obligated to maintain the confidentiality of personally-identifiable information and are subject to disciplinary action for any breach, up to and including termination. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Accordingly, and despite our efforts, AVMA cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, or to or from our online products or services. 

### Children Under the Age of 13

We do not knowingly solicit data online from or market online to children under the age of 13. 

### Advertisers on AVMA Websites

Some AVMA Websites may contain advertisements or links to the advertiser’s website. We do not control the websites of third parties reached through links on AVMA Websites or their information collection practices, and AVMA will not be responsible for the activities of these third parties. We encourage you to review the terms of use and privacy practices of all websites you visit.

AVMA Websites may also include links to third-party organizations that offer products and services, such as SmartBrief (offering the Animal Health SmartBrief), to members and other users of AVMA Websites. The AVMA does not control the privacy practices of these other organizations or what they do with any information you may provide them through their websites. We encourage you to review the terms of use and privacy policies of these other websites before providing any personal information.
